So what happens if one of your sanity checks fails?
如果你的一个完整性检查失败了怎么办呢？
>> Well it's kind of like monopoly.
这有点像垄断
If your sanity checks fail, do not pass go.
如果完整性检查失败 就不会通过
Do not proceed, go straight to analyzing why your sanity checks fail.
不能继续 直接分析为什么你的完整性检查失败了
You really have to debug and
你确实需要调试
understand what's going on before you can actually analyze your experiment.
在实际分析实验之前明白哪里出了问题
Because, if you try and
因为 如果你想略过它继续
move on past that, your conclusions are almost certainly wrong.
你的结论可能几乎全错
>> Okay, so how do you figure out what went wrong?
好吧 那你如何查明哪里出错了？
>> Well, there's a couple different avenues that you can try.
你试错的不同路径可以有好几个
First, something might have gone wrong technically, and
首先 可能是技术上出了问题
you want to work with your engineers to understand,
你要和你的工程师一起查明
is there something going on with the experiment infrastructure?
实验架构是否出了问题
Did I get the experiment set up correctly?
我的实验设置是否正确
Is something wrong with experiment diversion?
实验分组是否出错
You really want to debug the experiment setup with the engineers.
你真的需要和工程师一起调试实验设置
The second thing that you can try and do is a retrospective analysis.
可以尝试的第二件事是回顾性分析
Try and recreate experiment diversion from the data capture,
尝试从数据采集方面重新进行实验分组
and understand that this is something endemic to what you're trying to
明白这经常是导致这个情形的原因
do that may be causing the situation.
你要试着解决
The third thing is, we can try and use those pre and
第三件事是 我们可以尝试利用
those post periods we talked about earlier in lesson four.
之前在第四课中提到的实验前和实验后的时间段
Right?
对吧？
If you're in a pre-period, then you can say,
在实验前 你可以考虑
did I see the same changes in those invariance in my pre-period?
实验前在不变式中看到同样的更改了吗
If I saw them in the pre-period and the experiment, that points to a problem
如果在实验前和实验中都看到过 那问题就出在
with the experiment infrastructure, the set up, something along those lines.
实验结构 设置和相关方面
On the other hand, if you see the change only in your experiment but
另一种情况 如果你只在实验中看到了更改
not in the pre-period, that points to something with the experiment itself,
实验前没看到 那问题就出在实验本身上了
maybe the data capture or something along those lines.
可能是数据采集或相关方面的问题
>> Okay, what are the most common reasons you've seen for
好的 在数据不匹配的问题上
data not matching up like this?
你最常遇到的原因是什么？
>> Well, the most common one that I really see is data capture, especially
我遇到的最常见的原因就是数据采集了
when you want to capture a new experience that the user is undergoing.
尤其当你想采集用户正在体验的新实验数据时
Right? And so
对吧？
maybe you just didn't capture it correctly.
可能你的采集就不准了
Maybe the change triggers very rarely, and you capture it
也许很少导致更改 你在实验组中也正确采集了数据
correctly in the experiment, but you don't capture quickly in the control,
但你在对照组中没有快速采集
and so you're not comparing like with like.
所以没有进行同类比较
That's probably the most common.
这是最常见的问题
But other reasons could be, the experiment's set up.
但也可能是其他原因 像实验设置
So, for example, what happens if you have a filter to English only?
比如 你的筛选器只筛选英文怎么办？
Maybe you set up for the experiment, but not the control, and
可能你对实验组进行了设置 但没有设置对照组
now your publishes aren't comparable.
那现在你的结果就没有可比性
More rarely, it could be your infrastructure, or the ex, you know,
更少见一点的原因还有实验架构或
the experiment system, something along those lines.
实验系统 或类似方面
Maybe there's something going on to really sort of reset cookies, and
或许发生了一些事情 比如重设 cookie
that's what's sort of screwing things up.
这就会把实验搞砸
You just have to go through and test all of them.
你必须全部检查 全部测试
>> Okay.
好的
And is it ever just a real difference?
这个真的有区别吗
>> It could be, but it's probably not a good thing if it is.
有的 但可能不是件好事
For example, there's something in the infrastructure that's going on to cause
比如 实验架构中某些东西
the cookies to churn.
造成 cookie 混乱
You probably don't want that,
你可能不想要这种结果
your user's probably not having a good experience, and
你的用户体验可能并不好
it's not good for the experiment itself.
这对实验本身来说也不好
Right?
对吧？
Now the key thing to remember is that all of these comparisons,
现在记住一件重要的事 所有的这些对比
they're approximations.
都是近似值
So you're not going to get an exactly the same number.
所以你不会得到完全相同的数字
It's just going to be approximately the same.
只会是近似相同
The other thing that I get asked a lot is, well, maybe my users are learning
另一个我被问到的最多的事是 也许我的用户学习了一段时间
over time, maybe it's, you know, users are adapting to the change.
你知道的 可能用户正在适应这种更改
Now, the key thing there is that, if there really is a learning effect,
现在 关键的问题是 如果真的存在学习效应
then you're going to see not very much change in the beginning,
你在一开始看不到太多改变
and it's going to be increasing over time.
它是随时间增加的
So if you're seeing a big change right from the beginning,
所以 如果你从一开始就看到一个很大的改变
it's probably not a learning effect.
可能不是学习效应
>> Okay. And then if all the sanity checks do
好的 如果所有的完整性检查
pass, then we can analyze the experiment.
都通过了 接下来我们就可以分析实验了
>> Yes. Then you can analyze the experiment.
是的 接下来你就可以分析实验了